allegorithmic.com 2011-12-13

# Privacy Policy | Allegorithmic

Allegorithmic sas, a French corporate entity registered in the registry of commerce of Clermont-Ferrand under n° 448 617 753, located 31, Rue Gonod, 63000 Clermont-Ferrand, FRANCE, (hereinafter “Allegorithmic”) processes Personal Data (as defined below) of people browsing the [www.allegorithmic.com](http://www.allegorithmic.com/ "www.allegorithmic.com") website of Allegorithmic (the "Site").

This “Privacy Policy” lets You (as defined below) know how Allegorithmic collects and uses Your Personal Data and how You can control its use.

## 1\. SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy sets forth the principles and guidelines governing the protection of the Personal Data (as defined below) collected on or through the Site and concerning the Site’s visitors and users ("You" or "Your").

Personal data ("Personal Data") means any information relating to an identified or identifiable person. An identifiable person is a person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to the person.

Non-Personal Data means any information that does not result in the identification of a person.

The Site’s Terms of Use, which can be found at <http://www.allegorithmic.com/company/terms-of-use> are incorporated into this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Site and any Personal Data You provide on the Site are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and those Terms of Use.

## 2\. DATA COLLECTED

In order to use certain functions and features of the Site, Allegorithmic requires that You provide certain Personal Data when visiting or using the Site. Personal Data likely includes

  * first and last name,
  * postal address,
  * email address,
  * telephone number(s),
  * login and password,
  * company, company type, company size, position,
  * industry sectors,
  * delivery method and people to whom purchases must be shipped, and
  * any other Data as may be relevant for the purposes listed below.

In all cases, however, the Personal Data gathered is limited to data necessary to the purposes described under paragraph 4.

You are free to decide whether or not to provide all or part of Your Personal Data. However, if You choose not to provide all or part of this Personal Data, the purposes as described in paragraph 3 hereafter might not be achieved or not properly achieved, some areas and functions of the Site may not function properly and/or You may be refused access to certain pages on the Site. In particular, You will not be authorized to purchase products or services via the Site.

## 3\. PROTECTION OF PERSONAL DATA CONCERNING CHILDREN

Allegorithmic affirms its commitment to the protection of the Personal Data of children. In this respect, Allegorithmic does not knowingly collect, conserve or store Personal Data or Non-Personal Data of children under 18 years of age. Moreover, no part of the Site is directed to children under 18 years of age.

## 4\. METHODS AND PURPOSES OF COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA

As stated above, You provide Your Personal Data on a voluntary basis.

Allegorithmic will collect Personal Data either online or offline and this Privacy Policy is applicable regardless of the means of collection. In the case of online collection, this Privacy Policy is posted on the Site and in the case of offline collection, You will be notified this Privacy Policy.

Personal Data is generally collected to carry out the business of Allegorithmic, such as improving Allegorithmic’s marketing and advertising efforts, better tailoring Allegorithmic products and services to customers’ needs or complying with reporting obligations required by law, and similar activities.

Your Personal Data collected by Allegorithmic on or through the Site is used by Allegorithmic for the following purposes:

  * To enable You to request information;
  * To provide You with a personalised interactive use of the Site;
  * To ascertain Your requirements and interests and provide You with the most suitable products and/or services;
  * To allow You to open and maintain an account in order to obtain specialised documentation and technical assistance;
  * To enable You to subscribe to a commercial or support-type service;
  * To enable You to make online purchases of some of our products; and
  * To access all the features and options offered by the Site.

By providing Your e-mail address, You hereby expressly authorize, Allegorithmic and its subsidiaries to use it together with other relevant Personal Data to send You commercial or marketing messages.

Allegorithmic might also use Your email address for administrative or other non-marketing purposes (for example, to notify You significant changes to the Site).

Allegorithmic may use cookies or other technologies which collect or store Personal Data but only to: (a) keep information so that You will not have to re-enter it during Your visit or the next time You visit the Site and thus enhance Your browsing experience on the Site; (b) monitor aggregate metrics as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.

Cookies are text files stored and used to record non-personal and personal information concerning Your browsing of the Site. Allegorithmic uses two types of cookies: permanent cookies and temporary cookies. Temporary cookies disappear as soon as You log off from the Site. Permanent cookies remain after logging off from the Site in order to be used on subsequent visits to the Site. You may configure Your browser software so that You will be notified when You receive a cookie, and then You decide whether to accept it or refuse it. You can also configure Your browser software to refuse all cookies; if You do so, however, some areas and features of the Site may not function properly.

## 5\. PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING AND STORAGE TERM

Processing of Personal Data includes using, storing, recording, transferring, adapting, summarizing, amending, reporting, sharing and destroying Personal Data as necessary under the circumstances or as otherwise required by law.

All Personal Data that will have been collected will be stored for a limited duration that is relevant to the purpose of such collection and for so long as required by applicable law.

## 6\. LINKS TO WEBSITES NOT CONTROLLED BY ALLEGORITHMIC OR ITS SUBSIDIARIES

This Site might offer links to third party Websites which may be of interest to You.

Unless Allegorithmic receives Your express authorization, Allegorithmic does not share any Personal Data with these third parties. However, Allegorithmic may provide them with Non-Personal Data.

These third parties use technological processes to send advertisements and links appearing on the Site to Your browser software, via Your IP address. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript or web beacons) to assess the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize their content.

Allegorithmic does not exercise any control over the content of third party Websites or the practices of these third parties in connection with the protection of Personal Data that they might collect and are thus not in the control of Allegorithmic. Consequently, Allegorithmic declines all liability for the content of third party websites or the practices of these third parties concerning the protection of Personal Data.

It is therefore Your responsibility to inform yourself as to these third parties' privacy policies.

## 7\. TRANSFER OF PERSONAL DATA

If You are accessing the Site from a location outside of the European Union, with laws or regulations governing data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from European Union, please note that through Your continued use of the Site, which are governed by French law, the corresponding Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, You are transferring Your Personal Data to the European Union and You consent to that transfer.

You will have the opportunity to decide whether You authorize Allegorithmic to use Your Personal Data for a purpose differing from the purpose for which it was originally collected.

Allegorithmic will also disclose Personal Data to third parties if Allegorithmic determines that such disclosure is necessary for technical reasons (such as hosting services by a third party) or to protect Allegorithmic’s legal interests (such as in the event of acquisition or merger by a third company or total or partial liquidation of Allegorithmic).). These transfers may be transmitted over the internet, via mail, via facsimile, or by any other method which Allegorithmic determines is appropriate and in accordance with applicable law.

## 8\. RIGHT OF ACCESS TO AND RECTIFICATION OF THE DATA

Allegorithmic will take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Data collected is used for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy and that such Personal Data is correct and up to date.

You have a right to access Your Personal Data, as well as a right to request the rectification, completion, update or erasure of Your Personal Data. You also have a right to obtain a copy of the Personal Data conserved by Allegorithmic.

If You have an account, You can exercise Your rights of access to and rectification of the Personal Data by logging on to Your account. Otherwise, You may exercise Your rights of access to and rectification of the data by sending an email to the following address: privacy.policy(at)allegorithmic.com.

Depending on the scope of the request, Allegorithmic reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee to cover any out-of-pocket costs incurred in connection with such access, modification and deletion of Personal Data. Allegorithmic may deny access to Personal Data in limited circumstances, defined by applicable laws and regulations.

## 9\. DATA SECURITY AND RECIPIENTS

Allegorithmic undertakes to ensure the protection and security of Personal Data that You choose to communicate, in order to ensure the confidentiality of Your Personal Data and prevent Your Personal Data from being distorted, damaged, destroyed or disclosed to unauthorized parties.

Allegorithmic maintains reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation and destruction. As part of those safeguards, Allegorithmic employs sophisticated technology designed to protect Personal Data during its transmission and prevent transmission errors or unauthorized acts of third parties. However, while Allegorithmic strives to protect Your Personal Data, in light of the inevitable risks of data transmission over the internet, Allegorithmic can not guarantee full protection against any error occurring during the course of Personal Data transmission which is beyond Allegorithmic' reasonable control.

Since all Personal Data is confidential, access is limited to employees, contractors and agents of Allegorithmic who have a need to know such data in carrying out their tasks. All the people who have access to Your Personal Data are bound by a duty of confidentiality and subject to disciplinary actions and/or other sanctions if they fail to meet these obligations.

However, it is important for You to exercise caution to prevent unauthorized access to Your Personal Data. You are responsible for the confidentiality of Your password and information appearing on Your account. Consequently, You must ensure that You log out of Your session in the event of shared use of a computer.

## 10\. DISPUTE RESOLUTION

Although Allegorithmic has put in place reasonable safeguards to protect Personal Data, we recognize that there is no method of transmitting or storing Personal Data that is completely secure.

However, Allegorithmic is committed to ensure the privacy of Personal Data: if You have a reason to believe that the security of Your Personal Data has been compromised or misused, You should contact Allegorithmic via the following address: privacy.policy(at)allegorithmic.com.

Allegorithmic will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the principles contained in this Privacy Policy. .

Unauthorized access to Personal Data or the improper use of Personal Data may constitute offences under local law and under the regulations in force within Allegorithmic company.

## 11\. CONTACT

For any additional question concerning this Privacy Policy, You may send an email to the following address: privacy.policy(at)allegorithmic.com.

## 12\. DATE OF ENTRY INTO FORCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY AND CHANGES TO IT

This Privacy Policy may be updated according to Allegorithmic' requirements and circumstances, or where required by law.

Last modification: This Privacy Policy was modified on April 2011.
